Previously on "The 100"...
Where the hell is my daughter?
We didn't know she was
missing until today.
Nobody did.
We're gonna get everyone back.
I remember things.
Your sketchbook?
Madi, don't tell anyone that...
ever.
We need to get to our friends.
There's your bridge. Go.
You're coming with us.
Now move.
You should have more faith, Clarke.
My throne.
The book.
Bellamy...
_
Don't make me do this.
The fate of the entire
human race is at stake.
I have no choice but to share this.
I'm sorry.
Me, too.
Clarke!
What is it? What happened?
Where are we?
The Second Dawn bunker.
Otherwise known as hell.
Earth?
How?
This place is perfect for you.
Nano-tracking program.
What is it you say? May we meet again.
Welcome home, Mother.
Gaia?
Seda, how are you here?
Good question.
He turned off the stone.
Before the bridge
closed, we went through...
Landing here.
No. How?
The closing bridge defaults
to the planetary origin of our DNA.
Your journey ends here, too.
He would not
stop talking while we fought.
He said when you're
caught in a closing bridge,
it defaults to the
planetary origin of your DNA,
Earth.
For all mankind.
I'm no man.
Where's the head?
Buried with the rest of him.
Until today, no one
even knew you were missing.
How long have you been alone here?
A few days until the
others arrived this morning.
I thought it would be
the rest of my life.
We're together now.
Echo and Octavia...
where are they?
It's so green.
They're over here.
Earth is back.
Hey.
- Jax!
- Hey, baby.
Oh, it's good to see you.
I missed you.
- Hey.
- Hi.
- Hey!
- Hey.
It's good to see you.
Hi.
You weren't inside.
- Hey.
Where's Bellamy?
Clarke?
Dead.
He's dead.
Bellamy?
Clarke, he was fine when we left.
- I'm a little confu...
- I killed him.
I had to.
Why?
Madi's sketchbook. He had it,
and he knew that she still has
the memories of the Commander.
She would never be safe.
I begged him to stop.
I tried to get the book back,
but he...
I tried everything, I promise.
I tried.
I'm so sorry.
I understand.
So would the old Bellamy.
The one that would do
anything for his baby sister
and the people he loved.
You can hate me if you want to.
God knows I do.
We lost him a long time ago.
He needed all this chaos to make sense,
all the violence,
all the people we've killed.
He couldn't accept that
it's all meaningless.
Cadogan gave him meaning,
and that meaning is what killed him...
Not you.
No one wants to live here,
but it will do until we
build our own shelter.
There is a river close by,
so there is plenty of drinking water.
What about food?
You check the hydrofarm?
Nothing.
That whole level was
destroyed in the fire.
Where is Blodreina?
She didn't come back inside.
Avoiding her demons.
I don't blame her.
Have you found
another food source?
We hear birds, insects, so there must...
What about power, hot water?
That's it. I'm out of here.
Where's the funky ball
with the green light?
A way out is the
first thing we looked for.
There's no stone here.
No. There has to be.
That's how Cadogan got his people out.
We lived here for 6 years.
I think we would have seen it.
One way to find out.
Raven, we tried that.
Our helmets showed no
trace of the stone anywhere.
100 feet straight down.
They gave you trash helmets
so you couldn't get out.
Perfect. So we jump to Sanctum,
have a hot shower, stock up on supplies.
Bring my people home.
- Raven, can I?
- Yeah.
What the hell are you doing?
It's the only way out of here!
Earth is our home.
Everyone who is from here is here...
Everyone we care about,
and I will not lose anyone else.
Let's choose a room.
Pretty pictures, don't you think?
These restraints won't do at all.
You're lucky my people brought you here,
or you'd be dead right now.
I feel lucky.
Did you draw this?
No... but I know who did.
Ohh. Incredible.
Yes. Our medicine is incredible.
So is our ability to dig
through your memories,
but I'd rather save the time.
What do you want?
First, I'll need assurances.
Sanctum is mine.
We destroy the stone.
You people never come back.
The stones are indestructible,
but, yes, you can have Sanctum,
not that it'll matter.
I don't think you
comprehend what this means.
It means someone has memories
that are not their own,
memories that you require
in order to start a war
with whoever made the stones,
a war I want no part of.
One planet will be fine,
thank you very much.
Not a war, the last war,
and you'll be part of it
whether you like it or not.
How's that?
If we win, we transcend,
evolving beyond these meat
sacks that age and die,
becoming one with a
universal consciousness.
I like this meat sack. It's new.
- This will be better.
- Hmm.
And whether you fight with us or not,
even you will transcend.
Every member of the human family will.
Good luck with that.
Do we have a deal or not?
You fool.
If we lose, it won't
matter what planet you're on
or whether you're fighting.
Every member of the human family dies.
Clarke's child.
Madi.
Of course. Bellamy knew.
That's why she killed him.
Thank you.
She'll never
let you take her child.
I won't be asking.
Of course not. You'll send
a strike team no doubt,
they'll fight you, the child, as well.
If she gets killed, you'll have nothing.
- You have a better idea?
- Yes.
Send me.
- You?
- Mmm.
Who wants no part of this.
That was before I
knew what was at stake.
Although transcend or
die has a nice ring to it,
it really isn't much of a choice, is it?
I've been in the child's head.
I know her better
that she knows herself.
How well does your strike team know her?
I'll get her back, but
then our deal still stands.
Take him to the bridge.
I don't want to take inventory.
So don't.
We took everything we could carry
when we marched for the valley.
Do your remember our first
night in our desert tent?
Hey. You OK?
I told Bellamy I'd forgive him.
Now I can't.
Talk to me.
He forgave me for everything I did here.
I wonder if my father would do that.
I don't think he would.
Your father wanted you to live, Nate.
That's why he gave up
his spot in this bunker,
and you have.
You are.
Clarke's right.
Everyone we care about
that's left is here.
We thought Sanctum was
our second chance...
but I think this is.
Welcome to Niylah's rec room.
No cursing, no spitting, no killing.
Huh. No way. A piano.
I used to tickle the ivories.
Jordan, hold this.
It's been over 200 years, but, uh...
Out of tune.
What are you doing?
Ohh. There were too many
rules when we lived here.
I found my way around most of them.
- The bar's open.
- Ahh. Is it safe?
It was never safe.
God, that's awful.
It was your dad's recipe.
Smooth.
Echo.
I'm tired.
- I'll go with you.
- No.
I'm gonna.
She needs space.
And we need to drink.
Oh. No, no, thank you.
I'm tired, too.
My dad made it.
OK. Hmm.
- Oh, my...
- Ha ha ha!
- It's good, right?
- No. That's awful. Mmm.
Oh, man.
This'll do until we can
rebuild above ground.
Pick a bed. You'll be less
mad at me in the morning.
All these beds should
be filled with people.
Oh, Madi, I'm really
not in the mood to argue.
You decided for me...
again.
I decided for everyone.
That's what I do.
Just like you decided to kill Bellamy.
I did that to save you.
I didn't ask you to,
and now you have to live with that!
I don't want that for you!
I know you're mad that
I stranded us here,
but remember Shallow Valley,
when it was just us and all we
wanted was for our friends...
Your friends. What about mine?
I was starting to build my own life.
I have friends in Sanctum.
Picasso is there, Luca.
You think you're protecting me,
but you're not.
You ruined my life.
Just like you ruined your own.
Madi, wait.
This place is huge. You can't
just wander off in the dark.
I won't. Don't follow me.
Oh, let there be light.
That's my girl.
Well, thanks for your help.
Now we find the stone,
assuming you can fix this.
You're kidding, right?
I'm not a miracle worker, Murphy.
I beg to differ.
Come one. You know we can't
leave all those people on Sanctum
now that we know it's survivable here.
The people on Sanctum
are better off without us.
Until the next eclipse maybe.
Clarke is wrong.
Some of those people
are from here, Raven,
Wonkru, Eligius prisoners.
Earth is their home, too.
Let me ask you something.
When you let hatch and his buddies die,
was that just to save your friends?
We passed a workshop down here.
6 years of watching Bellamy
manipulate her on the ring.
Damn it.
I know.
I miss him, too.
Yeah.
_
Did Lincoln teach you that?
You weren't my only teacher.
No. Just the best.
It's your watch in the rotunda.
No way. I'm not going back down there.
Fine.
Then neither am I.
I told you once
we mourn the dead when the war is over.
So is it over?
I hope so.
I saw you days ago, but for you,
it's been 10 years on another planet,
yet still you haven't made peace
with what happened here.
I thought I did.
And then seeing the fighting pit again,
I don't know.
We did what we had to do to survive,
but if it is your penance to sit here
in the freezing cold,
then it is my penance, too,
because I am equally guilty
about what happened down there.
We were all Blodreina.
Now come on. We'll face
your demons together.
You win.
Conclave rules. Conclave rules.
Win the fight, save your life.
I used to resent when you
would look at her like that.
- Gaia.
- I don't anymore.
I am glad Octavia came to you.
She was always more warrior than I.
I am sorry that I wasn't.
I'm the one who's sorry.
My child, don't you know?
You're my Seda.
Here they come!
On me!
Gaia!
What was that? Why open
the bridge and not use it?
They used it. Someone's here.
I can feel it.
They're here for Madi.
Go warn Clarke.
I'll stay and make sure
no one else comes through.
I'm not leaving you again.
I'll go.
They're here for Madi.
Where is she?
We had a fight.
I have to find her.
Madi!
Hey. I like that song.
What? No.
Um...
I'm... I'm sorry. I...
This is the part where
you go after her, mi hermano.
Hi, Madi.
Madi's here?
Ohh.
There she is.
It's OK, Niylah. You
can drink in front of me.
Uh, she's had enough anyway.
What? I'm fine.
Madi?
If you can hear me...
She wasn't on level 6 either.
There's 4 more levels. We'll find her.
OK.
The party's over.
Grownups.
Will you play something else?
Ahh. I'll do better than that.
Have a seat. I'll teach you.
- Really?
- Yeah. It's easy.
It's only taken me 200
years to figure out.
Madi?
Answer me!
Hands like this. OK.
We're gonna play a C.
Madi!
You're drunk.
And you said you were tired,
but you're still up, so...
Why are you still up, Echo?
Not Echo.
Ash.
My name is Ash.
Don't worry. I never
told Bellamy either.
6 years,
and I never told him my real name.
Every day, I'd wake
up and think to myself
"today's the day."
But no.
When I finally told someone,
it was to save my life.
Echo was a coward.
No.
Not a coward. Human.
I wanted him to see me as
this person I've become,
not pity me for who I was
or what I went through or...
He did. He wouldn't have
stayed with you that long
if he couldn't see the real you, Echo.
I mean Ash.
You're not the only one with secrets.
I was named for Queen Nia.
What? But you're Trikru.
My father's side.
My mother was Azgeda.
That's why we lived so
far out in the woods.
So no one would see her scars.
We are who we choose to be,
and we don't owe anyone our pain.
What is taking you so long?
Miracles take time.
Hero Murphy's kind of freaking me out.
I know...
But it's hot.
I'm right here, and also I'm not a hero.
I just think the people on
Sanctum deserve to live on a planet
that doesn't eat them or
occasionally drive them insane.
Hey.
We haven't, uh, properly met. I am...
John Murphy.
I've heard stories.
I tend to play well in stories.
Hmm. Not these.
Those stories. Yes.
You OK?
Hey, Murphy.
I... got this.
OK. I was his favorite, though,
wasn't I, Jordan?
I am sorry I upset you.
I haven't spent a lot of
time with people, and...
sometimes I just misread things.
Yeah. Me, too.
I was having fun dancing,
- and I thought you...
- I was.
I just started to feel guilty.
I know.
I felt the same when I woke from cryo
and my parents were gone.
It takes time, but it does get easier.
We should get back.
You don't have to dance if you...
You know, let's dance here.
- There's no music.
- Mmm.
OK.
Madi, where are you?
Madi! Madi!
- Clarke?
- Hey, hey. What?
Whoa, whoa. What happened?
Is Madi with you?
Did you fix it? I
need to find the stone.
Oh, now you
want to find the stone?
I'm sorry, Murphy. You were right.
We need to leave.
Why? What happened?
Disciples are after Madi.
Has anyone seen her?
She's in the rec room.
- You're sure?
- Yeah.
No, no, no. No, no!
Madi!
E, E, F, G.
Yeah. It's that easy.
It's only 5 notes, but...
yeah, it almost feels... Familiar.
Hmm. That is the
beauty of Mr. Beethoven.
OK. Try again, but this time, I want...
Help! Get away from me!
Hello, Madi.
It seems you're the key to the
transcendence of the human race.
They sent me to bring you back,
but, you see,
I don't want to transcend.
I want to reign.
They gave me a choice...
Use these to bring you back peacefully
or this...
if you wouldn't go willingly.
I prefer option 3...
to gut you like a pig.
Go!
Indra's in the rotunda. Get help!
Help! Clarke!
Help!
Gaia, Indra!
Do you hear that?
- Help!
- It sounds like Madi.
- We let them in. On me.
- Gabriel needs help!
- Madi?
- He's here!
- Madi, what is it?
- Help! No!
You.
Me.
Us.
Madi, clear out.
_
Not today.
Murphy, give it up.
It's never gonna break.
You were saying?
Nice job, Murphy.
All in a day's work, my friends.
Thanks, Murphy.
All right. Let's go.
Gabriel.
Gabriel. No, no, no, no.
Hope... my friend.
I'm right here. I'm with you.
Where is she?
Madi.
Sheidheda.
I tried.
I'm right here.
Thank God. Are you hurt?
He saved my life.
Sheidheda got away.
He stabbed himself in the gut and...
disappeared.
I know how that works.
Cadogan will send more disciples.
We have to get
back to Sanctum now.
The stone.
Find the stone.
I couldn't fix the helmet.
Sheidheda's. He left it.
It's damaged.
It can't pinpoint the exact location.
The stone's here.
What'd we miss?
- Tell me what happened.
- I don't know.
No. No, no, no, no.
I'm ready.
What do you mean
the stone's here? Where?
I don't know.
We find it,
we go back to Sanctum, we get our army.
Clarke, you're
not going to war over me.
If they try to take you, I am.
All of us are.
No one else is getting
killed trying to protect me.
Madi!
- Maybe I should just...
- Absolutely not.
Do something!
Hope, I want this. It's OK.
In peace, may
you leave this shore.
In love...
No.
May you find the next.
Safe passage on your travels
until our final journey on the ground.
_
May we meet again.
God!
Madi?
Madi?!
The vent.
What?
Raven, Murphy, find that stone!
Madi, put the knife down.
Don't take another step.
I am sorry.
I did not know what she
wanted until it was too late.
Octavia said Cadogan would
just keep sending more people
until he gets me.
No one will ever be safe.
Madi, please don't do this.
I told you no one
else is dying to save me.
Madi... please.
I love you, Clarke.
No!
_
Be prepared!
They'll be invisible.
Bomb!
What the hell was that?
Emori, it was nothing. Come back.
Quiet. Listen.
Synced and corrected by Octavia
resync by nicolaspatate
- www.addic7ed.com -