The Blacklist'te daha önce.
Oturabilir miyim?
- Adım Anne.
- Raymond.
Bilemiyorum, Anne.
Hayatın oldukça dengeli görünüyor.
Öyle olduğunu düşünmek güzel.
- Sen ne iş yapıyorsun?
- Ben kaçağım.
Bazı insanlar tehlikeli yaşamayı sever.
Aklında ne var?
Senin bana yardım etmen.
Kız kardeşim için bir hediye bulmama...
Eşi benzeri olmayan küçük, küçücük
ikimizin ancak sığacağı bir
çikolata dükkanı biliyorum.
"North by Northwest"e ne dersin?
Yarın, Village East'te
gece yarısı
gösteriminde oynayacak.
Giriş kapısında seni bekliyor olacağım.
Raymond?
Anne, çok çok özür dilerim.
Bu gece gelemeyeceğim.
Mallar üzerinde güçlü bir konumdasınız.
Bakır, altın.
Ama asıl karınız kripto parada oldu.
Gördüğünüz gibi yılbaşından bugüne kadar
Bitcoin yüzde 800 kar getirdi.
Önemli bir konuma gelme konusundaki
ısrarlarınız çok öngörülü oldu.
Kazanmaktan sıkılacak
kadar zengin olmak güzel olmalı.
Sıkılmış değilim.
Sadece gideceğimiz için huzursuzum.
Başka bir randevumuz var.
Parasal durumumdan daha çok
endişelendiğim bir randevum var.
Geç kalıyoruz.
Briç hakkında ne biliyorsun?
Oyun olan briçten bahsediyorum,
köprüden değil.
Briç mi? Bilmiyorum.
Yatırımlarınızın ve varlıklarınızın
detaylı incelenmesi şu anki en önemli
- konu değil mi?
- Evet.
Önümüzdeki birkaç ay içinde,
uygun kaynaklara olan
ihtiyacımızın önemli ölçüde artmasını bekliyoruz.
Gördün işte.
Hepimizin farklı ilgi alanları
ve öncelikleri var, değil mi?
Mesela, sabahları Bay Zuma
ticaret bölümüyle başlar
ve sonra da spora geçer.
Bense karikatürlerle başlarım
ve koltukta uyuyakalırım.
Gazeteyi okumak tüm günümü alır.
- Karikatürleri seviyorum.
- Yani...
Karikatürleri de sever ama
ticaret ile arası çok iyidir.
Rakamlar, trendler falan. Gerisini biliyorsun.
Oysa ben Bitcoin ile
metro jetonunu ayırt edemem.
Ayırt etmene gerek yok.
Bitcoin elle tutulur bir şey değil.
Öyle değil mi? Bilmiyorum.
Bitcoin yatırımım
ne öngörülü ne de çılgıncaydı.
Sadece Bay Nakamoto'nun
talimatlarını dinliyordum.
Satoshi al dedi ben de aldım.
Satoshi Nakamoto mu?
Onu tanıyor musunuz?
O... Gerçekten o mu?
Evet.
Dembe benden daha iyi tanıyor onu tabii.
O ikisi resmen...
Görmemiz gereken
başka bir şey var mı?
Uçağa yetişmeliyiz.
Evet, şey...
Singapur ve BSE'deki varlıklarınız...
Pardon. Nakamoto'yu mu tanıyorsunuz?
Bildiğimiz Nakamoto.
Kimse Nakamoto'yla tanışmış olamaz.
Bay Cane, gerçekten gitmemiz gerek.
Yani sizin de gitmeniz gerek.
Peki, tamam.
Size yardım edebileceğim başka bir konu varsa...
İhale ya da koz döndürmeyi
bilmiyorsan yok.
Briç.
Hayır.
Neden endişelendiğimi
söyleyeyim mi?
Townsend...
Kafam çok karıştı.
Ne kadar okusam
o kadar az anlıyorum bu oyunu.
Orada seninle olmayacağım için bir de...
Raymond, ben ciddiyim.
Biliyorum. Seni bu yüzden seviyorum.
Ama bir sorun olmayacak.
İyi olacağım.
Tekrar yok. Bunu bana sen öğrettin.
Düşmanlarının bir adım önünde
olmak için ilk kural budur demiştin.
Bir şeyi bir kere yap. Fark edilmeyebilir.
Belki iki kere...
Ama ondan sonra, tekrara düşersin.
Bu kaçıncı ziyaret olacak?
Beş.
Ondan hoşlanıyorum.
Sığınacak bir yuvaya gelmeyi seviyorum.
Pencereden bir mum yandığını görmeyi...
Beni karşılamayı bekleyen gülümseyen yüzü...
Ben... Daha önce hiç sevmemiştim.
Şimdi seviyorum.
Tennessee'nin sembolünün süsen çiçeği
olduğunu biliyor muydun?
Kansas'ın sembol çiçeği hangisi?
Ayçiçeği.
Süsen çiçekleriyle büyüdü. Onları seviyor.
Seninle olmalıyım.
Sen, Raymond Reddington ile olmalısın.
Ben Anne'in yanındayken kendim değilim.
Olmak istediğin kişi olmayabilirsin
ama her zaman olduğun kişisin.
Yaşayan en seksi adamı
yeterince bekledik.
- Acele etme.
- Benim için
dakiklik önemlidir.
Belki uçağı rötar yapmıştır.
O zaman neden şimdiye kadar aramadı?
Çünkü dramatik girişler yapmayı severim.
Raymond! Süsen çiçeği!
Çok tatlısın.
Uslu olacağına söz ver.
Ne diyorsun? Çok uysal biriyimdir.
Şunları suya koyup sana sandviç yapayım.
Bran ve Lois'i hatırlarsın.
Evet, tabii ki.
Merhaba Bran, Lois.
- Selam, Ray!- Selam!
Umarım bugün üstüme çok gitmezsiniz.
Merak etme.
Cin ve tonik ister misin?
- Evet.
- Biz açılışı yaptık.
Sizi yetişeceğime eminim.
Pek sanmıyorum.
Tekrar doldurmam gerek.
Lois.
Ee, uçak rötar mı yaptı?
Evet. Bu aralar normal galiba.
Anne çok güven dolu.
Küçük bir yerde yaşadığımız için
korkacak bir şey olmadığını sanıyor.
Bu yüzden kapıyı kilitlemiyor.
Az önce kilitliydi.
Cidden mi?
Sen nasıl girdin o zaman?
Anne bana anahtar verdi.
Dinle.
Ben Annie'nin en yakın arkadaşıyım.
- Evet.
- Mutlu olmasını istiyorum.
Ben de öyle.
Güzel çünkü eğer bu işi batırırsan
seni öldürürüm.
Çeviri: oyington.
Pas.
Go Fish oynasak?
İhale böyle açılmaz.
Haklısın. Çıkmaza düştüm.
- İhale açamıyor musun?
- Pis yedili olur mu?
Olmaz mı? Peki.
Bir... kupa ile açıyorum.
Bir kupa.
- Bu olur.
- İki karo.
İki maça.
- Pas.
- Pas, galiba.
- Kupa valesi.
Sıra yine bende mi?
Hayır, sen battın.
- Biraz sert oldu.
- Elin battı yani.
- Kartları yere açık olarak koy.
- Teşekkürler.
Senin ortağın benim.
Elin batınca
bana iyi şanslar dersin.
Gelenek böyle.
Pekala, iyi şanslar, güzellik.
Şimdi gidip pastadan bir dilim alabilirsin.
Ben hepsini bitirmeden önce.
Herkes rahatlamış olur.
Şunları tokatla.
Anlatsana Lois, küçük bir yerde
polis memuru olmak nasıl bir şey?
Suç belgesellerini sevdiğim için soruyorum.
Öyle mi? Ben de!
Podcastleri ve Netflix
belgesellerini seviyorum.
Aynen! Onlara bayılıyorum.
The Staircase'i çok sevmiştim.
Yerden bir kupa kızı.
Ayrıca okumayı da severim.
İlk başta "Soğukkanlılıkla" kitabına
bağımlı olmuştum.
Sonra "Celladın Şarkısı".
Bunu alabilirim. Kupa ası.
- Onu okumadım, Ray.
- Okumalısın, Norman Mailer'ın.
Burada öyle şeyler olmuyor.
Şükürler olsun ki sakin bir kentteyiz.
Silahım var ama hiç kullanmadım.
Kullanacağımı da düşünmüyorum.
Zeki, tatlı, komik...
Hem de iyi bir aşçı.
Keşke.
Onu Cindi yapıp bize getirdi.
Otopark'taki o küçük kazadan sonra.
Küçük bir kentte böyle özür dilenir.
Tanrı Cindi'yi korusun.
Ve pastalarını.
- Sinek altılı.
- Sinek papazı.
Sinek yedili.
Nasıl tanıştığınızı anlatın hadi.
Yerden sinek dokuzlu.
Briç turnuvasında tanışmadığınız belli.
Parkta tanıştık.
Anne kuşları seyrediyordu.
Ben de Anne'i...
Bir Cape May bülbülünden konuştuk.
Sonra "North by Northwest" izlemeye
gidelim mi dedi.
Ve birinci dakikadan beni ekti.
Ama o zamandan beri telafi ediyor.
Hala devam eden
bir klasik film festivalimiz var.
Müzikal filmlerle başladık.
Filmin sonuna kalmadan uyuyor.
Bu gece değil.
Bu gece 1960lardan
İtalyan sinemasına başlayacağız.
Olamaz.
Kimse uyuyamaz.
Batan bile uyuyamaz.
Bu döner levhanın çalışabilmesi için
dış konnektöre yeniden
bir kablo lehimlemem gerekecek.
Lehim aletin yok, değil mi?
Hayır.
Bak ne diyeceğim.
Bir koşu hırdavat dükkanına gidip
orada var mı bakayım.
Kamyonu al.
Kiralık arabanın benzinini
harcamak istemezsin.
Anahtarların yerini biliyorsun.
Bir an önce dans etmeye başlayalım.
Ne oldu?
- Hiçbir şey.
- Hayır, hayır. Ne oldu?
Düpedüz 52 yaşındayım.
Bir adamla evliydim.
Lise aşkımla, 25 yıl boyunca...
Bir kitap kulübündeyim,
pazar günleri kiliseye giderim.
Ve nasıl olduysa
biriyle ilişki içerisindeyim.
"Dış konnektör" gibi kelimeler kullanan biriyle...
O bunu yaparken benim
tek düşündüğüm seks.
Zaten "dış konnektör" derken
benim de aklımda o var.
Tekrar yok.
Düşmanlarının bir adım önünde
olmak için ilk kural bu demiştin.
Pazartesi gitmek zorunda mısın?
Yani, zorundasın biliyorum. Ama...
Keşke gitmesen.
Kalmak için her şeyi yapardım.
Ama işlerin var.
Bu sefer özellikle...
stresli bir zaman.
"Stresli".
Yapmak ve korumak için
yıllarca uğraştığım bir şey
tehlike altında.
Senin için çok zor olmalı. Üzgünüm.
Senin için yapabileceğim bir şey var mı?
Zaten yapıyorsun.
- Ben ciddiyim.
- Ben de.
Dışarıda hayatım karmakarışık.
Buradaysa değil.
Sıkıntılarını azaltmaktan
fazlasını yapmak istiyorum.
Onları seninle birlikte taşımak istiyorum.
Sorunların ne olduğunu söylemezsen
bunu yapamam.
Anne.
Efendim?
Dans etmek ister misin?
Parmak izlerini araştırmış değilim.
Ama bunu yapmaktan çekinmezdim.
Suç belgeseli seviyor diye mi?
Ben de seviyorum.
Diyorum ki onun hakkında
neredeyse hiçbir şey bilmiyorsun.
Çok şey biliyorum.
Beni nasıl hissettirdiğini biliyorum.
Bir işi olduğunu ve
sorunları olduğunu biliyorum.
Ve o buradayken bütün
o sorunlar uçup gidiyor.
Ne işi? Ne sorunları?
Biliyorum, aşırı koruyucu bir arkadaşım.
Başkalarının işine karışmamalıyım.
Sadece, New York'tan kimseyle tanışmamıştım.
Hele ki saldırgan,
kaba ve tamamen narsist olan biriyle.
Bir kere o New Yorklu değil.
Ve Lois, bütün dünyaya görünmezim.
Ama ona değil.
O beni görüyor ve
onu bu yüzden seviyorum.
Gerçekten, seviyorum.
Sevdiğini biliyor muydu?
Hayır.
Artık biliyor.
Günaydın, hanımlar.
O kahve nefis kokuyor.
Günaydın.
Aç mısın? Çorek aldım.
Sağ ol, Lois!
Ama gevreği tercih ederim.
Narsistler böyle kahvaltı yapar.
So we can gaze admiringly at
our reflection in the spoon.
I better get on into the station.
Sorry.
Goodbye, Lois.
Have I told you about
the fork-tailed flycatcher?
She's right.
How they gather near
the elm trees south of town?
You know almost nothing about me.
I know everything I need to know...
Unless, of course,
those "business problems"
are a euphemism for a wife
or a husband somewhere.
No wife. No husband.
But there is a cat.
As well as other things
you should know about me.
About who I am.
Raymond. I know who you are.
You're someone who needs to see
the fork-tailed flycatcher.
Which I intend to show you,
just as soon as I find my binoculars.
I'm gonna go upstairs,
and you're gonna make us
some sandwiches to take with.
How's that sound?
It sounds just right.
I found two pairs and a blanket.
I found salami and cheese.
I'll get a basket for the food,
and we're good to go.
You told me the flycatcher
can range as far south as lower Mexico,
and some have even been spotted
as far down as Argentina.
What was that?
Nothing. I was just...
What were you saying?
I was saying... I was remembering
that you said you were thinking
about becoming a vegetarian.
That pipe dream was about 12 pounds ago.
That's something my doctor
is always bugging me about.
Didn't you say there was an excellent
vegan sandwich shop in town?
- But you're already making lunch.
- Which we can bring,
in case the tofurkey is inedible.
Why don't you run into town,
order for both of us?
I'll finish up, pack, and be
ready to go when you get back.
- Are you sure?
- Positive.
Okay. Two tofurkey sandwiches comin' up.
Oh. Hey, there.
Hey. Here on a call. Won't be long.
A call? Really?
What seems to be the problem?
County sent me.
Area's been having outages.
I just gotta check your
ground wires. It's standard.
Okay. Very good.
Vague, but detailed enough.
Delivered with authority.
I'm not sure what you mean.
You know what I mean.
Listen, mister, if it helps, I
got the work order right here.
Great.
Ugh!
How many are coming?
Everyone.
You found Arkham.
In a chest freezer in the garage.
His weapon's gone, vehicle's gone.
The girlfriend, Miss Foster.
Ping her cell.
She left less than 20 minutes ago.
Reddington wasn't far behind.
Wherever she's going,
that's where he's going.
Copy that. What do you want to
do about the missing vehicle?
Reddington.
This is between you and me.
It has nothing to do with her.
You must be referring to Miss Foster.
She has no idea who I am.
My family had no idea who you were.
They didn't know why they were
singled out or targeted,
but that didn't prevent their suffering.
You still have time to rethink
this. It's not too late.
It's interesting to me
how you speak as if you have
any say in how this
will end for you, Raymond...
as if it can somehow
be resolved in a civil manner.
The one thing I can assure you of...
The one thing... is that
what is about to happen
is going to be anything but civil.
They got a track
on the woman's cell.
She's close.
I have a second team
on their way to her now.
- Anne.
- Hey. What are you doing here?
If you needed something else,
you could've called me.
I need you to come with me.
Is that blood on your hand?
What happened?
I'll explain in the car.
Raymond, are you okay? I-I don't...
What's... What's going on?
Stay with me.
Raymond, please, where are we going?
- Give me your phone.
- Raymond, what on earth is wrong?
- Your phone, please.
- Raymond, you're scaring me.
What's going on? And who's that woman?
Here.
Hello. Can I help you?
- You should leave.
- Is that a gun?!
Raymond!
Here. Come with me.
No! Answer my question!
What is going on?
I'm not who you think I am.
I have another life, and
that life found us here today.
We are in danger, and
I need to keep you safe...
Someone wants to hurt you?
They want to hurt us.
Here. Stay here. Stay quiet.
Only open the door if it's me.
Anyone else, shoot. Do you understand?
Just point and pull the trigger.
- Anne.
- Raymond.
- W-What did you do?
- We have to go.
Who was that woman?
- Please, just try and keep up.
- Where are you taking me?
I don't want... stop! Let go of my hand!
Anne, please. Listen to me.
There are people coming for us.
It's not safe. You need to come with me.
Come with you where?
Officers, may I have
your attention, please?
- I'm sorry to interrupt.
- What are you two doing here?
May I please have your attention?
- My name is Raymond Reddington.
- Listen to what he has to say.
I'm a wanted fugitive. I have
two firearms on my person.
- Gun!
- Someone will need to disarm me.
Lois, we have a situation.
I need you to listen to me
very carefully.
Chief! Agent Barnes again on three.
- Says they have confirmation.
- Agents en route?
In the air now. 40 minutes out.
Within 40 minutes, everyone in
this building could be dead.
You really are him.
Lois, you need
to get her somewhere safe.
Now. We don't have much time.
You need to contact the highway patrol
and sheriff's department
and any available units
- from other counties.
- Can someone shut him up?
Chief, I got someone from the
D.C. field office on line two.
They are coming here.
Dangerous, highly trained mercenaries.
He's not making it up.
I saw him kill a woman.
Kill who?
Lois, look at me.
I am the most wanted man to
ever come through those doors...
By a lot... And I came here by choice,
not to surrender myself,
but to protect Anne
from the very bad men who are coming.
You need to get her somewhere safe,
because they will not be
intimidated by the fact
that you're the police.
They will assault this building
and kill everyone inside to get to me.
Please, get on the mutual-aid
band and scramble any units
within earshot, because this
is happening right now.
It isn't just Wichita
coming for you, friend.
Kansas City suits are on
the way, a team out of D.C.
Chief, will you
take a look at this?
Anne, talk to me. What do you
mean he killed someone?
- Killed who?
- I don't know who she was.
You saw him do it?
Neither one has plates.
You may want to get away
from those doors, Chief.
- What is happening?
- They're here, aren't they?
Lois, I am begging you.
You've got to get your boss
to enact lockdown protocols.
Get on the radio,
whatever cavalry you have,
call them in, now!
She doesn't have
the authority to give that order,
and you sure as hell
aren't authorized to give it.
You need to get ahead of this, Chief.
Sir, he's right. Whatever
this is, we are not equipped.
Okay. Here's what we're gonna do.
I want all nonessential
personnel out of the building.
Beth, get the others
and go out the back.
Pembry, find out what units
County has in the area
- and where they are!
- Brandt, notify Butler
and Lyon counties
and put local EMS on standby.
Who are you?
You need somewhere safe
where you can hide.
That was Reeves.
There was an incident in town,
but they have eyes on Reddington.
What kind of incident?
Landon. She's gone.
- And Reddington?
- He took the woman
and went into the local police station.
Ah. Raymond.
You do keep things interesting.
How you wanna handle this?
Put Sagan on the police scanners
and have him give us a timeframe.
If we're going to do this, it's
gonna have to happen fast...
and happen now.
I just spoke to County.
They're sending units now.
Gonna take Anne to Emporia
and hold her there
until we have a better handle on this.
You can't wait for units.
You need to get her out of here now.
Feds are 20 minutes out.
How could you not tell me?
I let you into my life, my home.
I never wanted to draw you
into my life, Anne.
I only wanted to escape into yours.
How selfish...
You getting involved with me
while knowing all of this
was hanging over us.
I let my feelings for you
cloud my judgment.
I am so sorry.
When this is over...
so are we.
Chief, take a look at this.
That second SUV moved.
It repositioned around back.
We have a third out front now.
Cottonwood Falls Police. Chief Russell.
Chief! How wonderful.
I presume you're the man in charge.
I am. Who is this?
I am the one who is here
for Mr. Reddington.
I'm confident he's explained
the situation to you by now.
You also know the closest units
are nine minutes out,
which gives me eight minutes
to acquire my prisoner.
Send him out now, you live.
Surrender and walk away, you live.
Stay and protect him,
and we kill everyone
who stands in our path.
You have 60 seconds to send him out.
Okay. Hold on. Let... Let's
start with who am I speaking to?
Fifty-five.
- Chief?
- Fifty.
These guys are heavily armed.
They're surrounding the facility.
Hold on. L-Look. Anne, get down.
Why don't I come outside and we
can talk, have a conversation?
Forty-five.
You still there? Can you hear me?
Look. I don't care who you are.
I'm not gonna bend to your demands,
and I'm certainly not gonna
send a man to his death,
even if he is a known criminal.
What I will do is talk to you
until we come up with
some reasonable compro...
Chief!
That was unfortunate.
But let's hope whoever
is second-in-command
can be more reasonable.
Send out Reddington.
Now you're in charge.
Shots fired. Repeat. Shots fired.
We have active shooters
on site. Officer down.
Requesting backup.
We got state troopers
east of Elmdale headed our way.
County units are still
eight minutes out.
If you have a weapons cache, open it.
We need to take positions
and push them back now.
- I'm not giving you a weapon.
- Staying alive until
backup arrives is
the only thing you can do.
No. You know what I can do?
End this by giving them what they want.
- What does that mean?
- Look. Stop!
We're not sending him
out there to be massacred.
- I am not protecting him!
- Hold on!
- Keep your heads down.
- She's right, Brandt.
We can't send him out there.
They'll kill him.
- Just let me think this through.
- What is there to think about?!
I am not dying for him.
The Chief already did that.
- Brandt, stop!
- Do not go out that door.
I'm coming out!
I'm unarmed!
You can see that, right?
No games.
I just want to walk away.
Oh!
That man has two children!
I thought police understood
rules. I told you the rules.
You don't get to change your mind.
I gave you 60 seconds
to send Reddington out.
You ignored me, so now I'm coming in.
The only thing that can stop
that is sending Reddington out.
No?
Okay. Be right there.
You need to uncuff me.
Lois, I can give them what they want.
I'll uncuff you, but
you're not going out there.
No. What are you doing? You can't!
Annie, he's Raymond Reddington.
If we're gonna survive this,
he's the only chance we've got.
I'm removing these cuffs,
but so help me God,
if we get out of here alive,
I am arresting you.
If you try to escape, I'll
shoot you. Do you understand?
Given the circumstances,
that's not much of a threat.
But, yes, I understand.
Maybe we should give Anne a sidearm.
- I don't want one.
- It could save your life.
Give it to her.
This is for our defense only.
If this building is breached,
and only if it's breached,
you have my authorization to...
Chase County Sheriff,
this is Officer Ethan Pembry.
How far are those units?
The detention cell!
Is it fully enclosed?
It is, but we can't access it!
- What? Why not?
- I don't have the keys.
- Brandt does.
- Brandt?
- I can get them.
- No, no, no!
- We have to!
- It's too dangerous!
No, Lois! No!
No, no, no!
Aah!
Get her to the holding cell.
There we go.
Keys. Where are the keys?
Here. Here.
Okay.
Well. Look what we have here.
Three ducks in a barrel.
Anne. Keep your eyes on Lois.
Get the door off.
Just ignore him.
Heh! This certainly is interesting.
Give me your scarf.
Mr. Reddington!
Take her hand.
Hello?
You should have left her
out of this, Neville.
It's over.
This was between us.
You're coming with me, Raymond.
We're ending this today. Here.
Yes, I'd like to agree with you,
but then we'd both be wrong.
So, in turn, how about this...
Take your men and your guns...
and your bloodshed... and go.
Then come find me when you're ready,
and I'll show you the proper way
to exact revenge.
Sir? We need to go. Right now.
The medics will be here any minute.
- Keep pressure on the wound.
- Mm-hmm.
I'm sorry, Anne. I wish I
belonged here with you, but I don't.
No. Stop.
I told you if we survived this,
I'd arrest you.
You're under arrest.
It's all right. You okay?
Yeah.
FBI.
She needs a doctor.
Station's clear. We need paramedics.
- Did you find Reddington?
- He was here?
Clear!
- I tried to stop him.
- You didn't find him?
Not yet, but knowing he was
here, we'll drop a net so wide,
even he won't be able to escape.
- Who did this?
- My friend.
I'm not sure where
you learned this, friend,
but you saved her life.
Reddington was in town visiting you?
I didn't know who he was.
I'm told he came quite often.
That's right. He did.
But you didn't know who he was?
You mean, was my life so boring
that I was willing
to spice it up by dating
an international fugitive?
No. It was not.
But it turns out it was boring
enough for me to get suckered
by an international fugitive
into thinking he cared about me.
Now that I know the truth, believe me,
if I can help you find him,
well, that would be my pleasure.
Glad to hear it, because
I have a lot of questions.
And I'll answer every one,
but I need to go home first.
One of my men will accompany you.
She's a victim, not a suspect.
She's also my oldest friend.
I don't want you hounding her.
I just need to shower, change,
and have a good cry.
And then I'll answer
anything you want to ask.
My car's in the lot.
Mind taking it home?
Of course not. I'll be at the hospital
just as soon as I've answered
their questions.
I wish we'd caught him.
But knowing he's out of your life,
I do get some satisfaction in that.
I told you if we survived
this, I'd arrest you.
You're under arrest.
Anne watched you kill someone.
I saw you kill three more.
We're alive because of that.
Not my chief. Not Pembry or Brandt.
They're dead because of you.
I kept telling them
what they needed to do,
and they didn't do it.
You were right. About him.
The wolf in sheep's clothing.
But you were wrong, too.
- Anne, don't.
- You don't understand.
- You need to move!
- I can't.
I won't.
Lois said to take the Falls Road
east out of town.
Most of the staties
don't even know it exists.
Nobody will be watching.
She's a good friend.
The best.
The man who came after you today...
Neville Townsend.
He won't stop, will he?
You were right. At the station.
Us, getting involved.
It was selfish of me.
It put you in harm's way.
It still puts you there.
If I'm in trouble either way,
why can't we be together?
Because what I have to do
and how I have to do it,
you can't be a part of that.
No one should be a part of that.
It won't be safe here until it's done.
I understand.
Is there somewhere you can go?
And not to your daughter's.
They'll anticipate that.
My friend Cindi,
the one who made the cake.
She has a cabin.
Call her. See if you can go there.
When it's safe,
you'll receive a postcard.
It'll be from the Corn Palace
in Mitchell, South Dakota.
That's how you'll know it's me.
But you don't know the address.
I have certain... capabilities.
Too bad staying awake for
a movie isn't one of them.
Ahh...
Thank you.
For what?
For... all of it.
Every... Every bit of it.
Except the bridge.
Of all the things that
happened on this trip,
the bridge scared me the most.
Take care, Dummy.
You take care, Anne.
Yes. Y-Yes.
Sam's Diner. Route 28.
I should be able to ditch
the car and be there in an hour.
And, Dembe...
you definitely should have come with me.
Yeah. O-Okay.
...by another ten days,
uh...
...is starting to...
♪ For it was I who chose to start ♪
♪ I see no reason to take me home ♪
♪ I'm old enough to face the dawn ♪
Ah, damn it.
Anne. Annie.
Elizabeth.