Of course, we'll kneel.
Was there ever even a question?
These are yours.
Ah. Why do I get the
feeling this is good-bye?
The palace is mine now.
So is the farmhouse. For you, that...
We'll take the machine shop.
You need a mechanic to run
the reactor. She's your girl.
Besides, you wouldn't want
your favorite chess partner
to live in a tent, would you?
Fine. Go. Who's next?
_
Kneel so that you can fight another day.
Good. I still get to kill you.
Convicts, Children of Gabriel,
welcome to the new Sanctum.
Things have changed quickly,
but the future is full of promise,
and to reap the benefits
of this bright, new day,
I ask only that you take a knee
to show your loyalty,
a simple gesture that
binds you to a contract
with a single rule...
If at any time you do anything
that I deem disloyal,
you die.
And if we refuse?
You die.
In that case,
the killers and the thieves
of Eligius exploration ship number 4
are at your service.
Nelson.
My name is Sachin.
My people and I swore and oath.
Better to die free
than worship at the feet of false gods.
I will not kneel
tonight or ever.
Does this man speak for all of you?
Surely some here would prefer to live.
One small genuflection,
and life goes on,
one Sanctum under me
for the benefit of all.
You stand by your principles,
and your people stand by you.
Those are the qualities
of a true leader.
There is only one leader in Sanctum.
Kneel before him or die.
Death... is life.
_
We were so close.
Bill, I know you're upset.
Upset? Why would I be upset,
just because we're back to square one,
randomly entering codes?
You told me Clarke had the key.
Actually, Octavia's memories did that.
You just never saw the
moment the Flame came out.
You let me believe it never did.
My Shepherd, may I have a moment?
Of course.
Everybody out.
You look good in white.
Lock him up with the others.
Let's go. Move it.
You're wondering what will
happen to your friends.
Yes, my Shepherd.
Join me, please.
Mmm. Broth.
I'd have killed for this
during my time on the mountain.
I heard about First Disciple Anders.
I assume you two were close.
I'm very sorry.
Close?
I met him twice.
I usually only meet the first disciple
once when they come to
wake me every 20 years
to say there's been no
progress to the last war.
Anders woke me twice.
The second time, we had found the key,
so, yes, I suppose, I mean,
comparatively speaking,
we were close,
but that's not what you meant, is it?
You were testing me to see if I live
by the same code that I
expect of my disciples.
Yes. Forgive me.
I don't want to cause you
any more pain, Bellamy,
but your friends have to
pay for what they've done.
Their crimes go beyond Anders.
Dozens of disciples are
dead because of them.
What if there was a
way to fix the Flame?
- Bellamy.
- With the technology you have here,
it could be possible.
And you'll help me get it
as long as I don't harm your friends?
Don't be ashamed.
The path is new to you.
I've walked it for centuries,
and it's still hard.
You remind me of my son Reese.
He went in search of the Flame.
I never saw him again.
I think my daughter killed him.
I'll never know for sure.
Well, if I can get the Flame
and your daughter really is in there,
you can find out.
All right. If you can get it
and if we can repair it
and if it contains the
code to the last war,
your friends will be absolved.
It's so good to see both of you.
Echo, your face.
Tell us this is a joke.
These clothes, the way
you betrayed us to Cadogan.
Tell us this is part of some plan.
Keep your voice down.
They are listening,
- and we don't have much time.
- Here's the part
where you tell us how screwed we are.
Very. You're to be executed.
There is one thing that
can stop it, the Flame.
The Flame that you told
Cadogan we destroyed?
We believe it can be repaired.
We?
I don't know where it is.
Raven, you were there.
Who took it after it came out of Madi?
I don't know, and if I did,
I wouldn't tell you.
Yes.
Take this one to M-Cap.
Bellamy, no!
Get off me don't touch me.
So much for family.
Move.
Who the hell are you?
I'm the man you love.
The man I love would not
be OK with torturing Raven.
It's not torture.
It is if you fight it.
I know these people, Bellamy.
I trained for 5 years to pass as one.
Then I spent another 3 months,
and I actually became one,
all so I could save you
and then avenge you.
I'm sorry you went through that.
Are you?
Because it looks to me
like while I was out there
doing everything I could to get to you,
you were forgetting me,
forgetting your friends,
who your family is.
I scarred my own face to remind myself
of who I was and where I came from
so I wouldn't lose myself while
I let them play with my mind.
You've lost yourself, Bellamy.
This isn't you.
I'm trying to save all of you.
And what happens if you
can't find the Flame?
You just gonna stand by and watch
as they execute us?
You know I don't want that.
That's not what I asked.
What do you do when you believe
in something with all your heart
that people you love think is crazy?
I don't know.
Watch us all die, I suppose.
Is this thing you believe in
really that important?
Is it more important than us?
Yes.
The end of war,
no more senseless death
or killing.
The Shepherd can deliver us there, Echo.
All of us,
for all mankind.
_
Isn't that right, Indra?
Excuse me?
Oh, you heard me. You hear everything.
What about her daughter?
Gaia. She's among the missing.
We believe she's in
the woods with a group
led by Clarke Griffin.
They're armed and extremely dangerous.
Indra led a search party to find her.
I was on it.
There's no sign of them,
but we did see this.
_
Why do you have Madi's book?
We have a deal.
I kneel to you, the child is spared.
Well, that was before she went
into hiding with my enemies.
- Are you my enemy, Indra?
- No.
Tell me where she is.
I don't know.
Have Trikru clean up this mess.
You, convict.
Come.
_
Play dead.
The coast is clear.
You can come out now.
It's OK.
We got clothing and medical supplies.
Jackson said to only change
the grossest bandages.
Prioritize the antibiotics.
Highest fevers only, you understand?
There's no food.
We're working on that.
Jackson's getting us some bread.
Maybe we should just kneel.
What? No. Trey, everybody
down there, including you
lost people at Sheidheda's big debut.
He knows that.
You're scared, but if he lets you live,
eventually that fear's
gonna turn to anger.
You're gonna want
revenge and rightfully so.
He will kill you to prevent that.
What are we supposed to do?
We can't just hide down there forever.
We are working on that, too, I promise.
And we trust you.
Come on, Trey. Let's
pass this stuff out.
I was right to believe in you.
I'm proud of you, too.
Yeah? What for?
Trey's right. Hoping that we survive
long enough for our
friends to come and save us
is not a plan.
You're smiling?
Heh. Sorry. It's just...
you're not worried about yourself,
and I find that...
incredibly sexy.
Hmm. Behavior that greatly increases
our risk of death is sexy to you?
- Who knew?
- Yeah.
- Ooh!
- Oh, ow.
Ha! Ow.
It's no castle. Ha ha!
No.
Even a cave... garage...
with you, all of them are castles.
Is it Jackson again?
I don't think so. Stay here.
Indra.
What the hell is that?
What have you got?
Sheidheda slaughtered
the Children of Gabriel.
They didn't kneel.
All of them?
Almost all.
Hey. Hey. It's OK.
It's OK. I got you,
kid. Come on, come on.
Hey.
Can you protect him?
I think we might know a place.
You're safe now. Come on.
Hey. Yeah. OK.
There's more.
Sheidheda is looking for Madi.
If he finds her, he'll kill you, too.
Yeah. Trust me, I'm aware.
Do you have any weapons?
Nuclear reactor count?
I'm proud of you, Murphy.
Yeah. Get in line.
Hmm.
OK. Here we go.
What happened?
It's not his blood.
Take him to the decon
shower, clean him up.
Don't push him to talk.
Yesterday, he lost
his biological parents,
and today, his people were killed.
What can I do for him?
Just be there, be his friend.
Indra?
No, but she said you could hide me.
Did she now?
Because I think Indra
knows me better than that.
Hiding people from a one-eyed
mass-murdering dictator
not really a survivor's move.
Neither is not inviting me in. Drop it.
Sheidheda asked me to follow her.
I'm so glad it led me here.
- Open the reactor door.
- I don't know the code.
- First one goes in your leg.
- Fine. Easy, easy.
OK, OK, OK.
- 1...
- Don't shoot.
2...
Hands where I can see them.
Nice and slow.
Jackpot.
Hey. How'd I look on camera?
Oh, good.
- She followed Indra?
- Yeah.
You know, I'm starting to
miss being a live coward.
It might help to talk about it.
We're not friends.
Why would I talk to you?
Good question.
Maybe because I'm the only one here...
or maybe because you
don't have any friends,
which I can totally relate to.
I was raised alone on a spaceship.
You were raised alone on a planet.
We both heard stories
about all the people
we're now surrounded by,
but they're not our friends.
When I was 10, the people here
abducted my mom and Octavia.
I was left alone,
and a man, a prisoner came,
and he was my friend.
He raised me.
He trained me. We...
we were gonna rescue them.
I got him killed because
I was too scared to kill,
and I vowed I would never
make that mistake again...
And I didn't...
up until the moment I
killed my own mother,
so do you still think we're the same?
Your mom died a hero.
You weren't there.
She saved everyone here,
but I doubt that's why she did it.
You were not there!
She did it to save you.
I wish she hadn't.
She didn't do it to
save your life, Hope.
She did it to save your soul.
I c...
Hey.
It's OK.
Ohh. Why?
I don't know.
I don't.
Oh, it hurts.
Let it out.
Something funny?
Because I don't see
anything humorous about this.
I'm smiling because I realized
I finally understand you.
Really? How so?
You have Madi, I have Hope.
I'd do anything to keep her safe.
How long were you on Penance?
We call it Skyring.
10 years. Good ones.
What?
A couple of days ago, she
was just our little girl.
Now she's messed up like the rest of us.
You need backup to talk to us now?
It's OK.
It's about time.
I have been racking my brain,
trying to figure out
how you telling Cadogan
the truth about the Flame helps us.
You know what I've come up with?
It doesn't.
I couldn't lie to him.
Really?
Why not?
I had an experience,
something that changed me to my core,
something that explains
why we're still here
and where we're going.
It came to me in a vision.
Mom was there.
The Shepherd led me to her,
and there was a light,
and it was beautiful
and warm and peaceful,
and I chose it,
and when I opened my
eyes, the storm had passed
just like that.
- Bellamy...
- Clarke, I...
I know how this sounds, but it's real.
A war is coming,
the last war we will ever fight.
Win it,
and we become the light.
Is that what the cult leader told you?
Did he tell you what happens if we lose?
- We won't.
- We turn into crystal,
wiped out
like Medusa turning people into stone.
It's the end of everything.
Not everything, just us.
If I told you the AI
that destroyed the Earth
was storing our minds
in the City of Light,
would that be any more believable?
What about a group of astronauts
turning themselves into gods
by transferring their
minds into the bodies
of their own followers
in order to live forever?
OK. Yes. We've seen our share of crazy,
but that doesn't change the
fact that fighting some war
to become the light is as ridiculous
as the clothes you're wearing.
There's one way to find out.
Tell me where the Flame is.
No.
Clarke, yesterday,
you were offering it up
in exchange for safe passage.
Yesterday, I was bluffing.
I made a deal to save my friends,
knowing damn well I had no intention
of following through with it.
Today, I'm standing in
front of my best friend,
who I thought was dead,
and I don't even recognize him.
Clarke, I am the same person
who brought you back from the dead,
who refused to give up on you.
There is so much more at
stake here than you know,
and I know you don't
believe in transcendence,
but I'm telling you it's real,
and I am asking you to believe in me.
Even if you're right,
even if everything
you're saying is true,
I will not help that man start his war.
Tell me where the Flame is.
Or what?
Dozens of disciples are dead,
including First Disciple Anders.
Yes, and every one of them
has tried to keep us
from saving our friends.
And now I am trying to
save you, all of you.
Clarke, if you don't
tell me where it is,
they will execute all of you.
Please let me help.
Go float yourself.
Guards.
Take this one to M-Cap.
What?!
Come on. Let's go.
Hey. Wait.
Bellamy, what are you doing?
What I have to do.
They all hate me.
They don't know what we know.
When we transcend,
they will understand.
For all mankind.
Our guest is awake.
Yeah, and she snores worse than you do.
Hey. It's OK. She can't hurt anyone.
You know, actually, I've been
wondering about something.
You think Hatch would have kneeled?
I bet he would have.
I think he probably would have even made
Sheidheda think he was working for him.
He wouldn't have actually done
the work, though, would he?
Yeah. That's what I thought.
You see that patch over there?
Hatch and I welded that into place.
See, he already knew he was gonna die.
All his men were down, and Raven,
in one of her more questionable moments
that I nevertheless respect,
locked me in here with him.
She didn't think he
was gonna finish the job
once he knew, but he did.
You know why?
To save you.
That's what he said.
Now... ahem... if you
don't stop freaking out,
we are gonna have to
hold you in the core,
where the radiation from the reactor
that he helped keep from melting down
will eventually kill you.
His sacrifice will be worthless.
Personally, I don't want
to see that happen. Do you?
Good. Look. When this is all over,
we'll drink to him in the tavern, OK?
OK.
All right. I'm awesome.
Apologies, my Shepherd,
but the neural link won't engage
with her fighting like this.
Keep trying.
Clarke, tell us where the Flame is.
Sir, she's dangerously
close to hemorrhaging.
Sir,
I don't think she knows.
She does...
Or she wouldn't be fighting.
Turn it off.
I'm sorry, Bellamy.
You did what you could.
Send the first of her
friends to Penance.
Wait.
I'll take you to it
but only once all my friends are safe.
Done.
Bellamy.
It didn't have to be like this.
Yes, it did.
Let the others do that, Indra.
You ordered Trikru
to clean up the blood.
I'm Trikru.
Don't remind me.
When you're done, clean yourself up.
The festivities are about to begin.
Heda, for you.
Oh, my, knight.
Hmm.
It's perfect.
There's more, Heda.
Bring it in.
Saved the best for last.
The convict you had follow
Indra has gone missing.
Fortunately, I took it upon myself
to have that convict followed.
Fine.
Then we won't eat either.
After the deathwave,
I didn't eat for more than two weeks.
Deathwave?
A wave of radioactive
fire taller than any tree.
The fire jumped our valley.
The radiation didn't.
Everyone I knew died.
My parents.
I was alone for 58 days.
I still dream about it sometimes...
but Clarke helped me through it.
Friends can be good at that, too.
I wish I knew you as a kid.
How about we go back upstairs,
finish what we started?
John!
You think they have engine troubles?
- Here.
- What?
- Stay here.
- No. I'm coming with you.
He'll expect to see both of us.
So we got in a fight.
You went for a walk.
Don't worry. I'll sell it.
What if you don't?
You'll be on the wrong side of the door.
You'll be on the right side.
I've got this.
I'm coming back.
Oh, thank God you're back. I...
Hmm. You're not Emori.
May we come in?
It's a little late.
- He knows.
- Yeah. I figured.
Hmm.
Open it.
What, the reactor?
I like you, John,
but our relationship's at a crossroads.
Open that door,
and you and your
Frikdreina girlfriend live.
I told you not to call her that.
Hey. Cyclops.
- Hmm.
- Yeah. That's right.
If anything happens to John,
I blow the reactor.
If you try to come in here, guess what.
They're bluffing, Heda.
Are they?
Everyone in there
knows that they're dead
the second that door opens.
In life, that's called
having nothing to lose.
In chess, I believe that's called a...
Stalemate.
Game's not over yet, John.
King takes knight!
Stay here, wait them out.
When the door opens, kill them all.
Why are they still restrained?
We had a deal.
Clarke, what is this? What deal?
He releases all of us,
and I take him to the Flame.
You'll forgive me if I have trust issues
where you're concerned.
Remove the restraints one at a time.
Any violence
will be met with lethal force.
No one is getting
violent. It's a good thing.
You're being released.
Helmet on to protect your memory.
You good with this?
Helmet on.
Let's go.
Now you.
Helmet on.
Hands up.
Sending the fighters first, is that it?
Can't be too careful.
Move it.
Let's go.
Go ahead. Step through.
Next.
What are you doing?
Ensuring you keep your part of the deal.
He didn't send them to Sanctum.
Correct, and thank you for demonstrating
why I didn't send you with them.
We know how the Stone works.
Also correct.
Where are they?
They're safe as I
promised they would be.
I said nothing about
releasing them on Sanctum.
You knew about this?
He doesn't know where
they are. Only I do.
I told you, Clarke, I don't trust you.
I do, however, trust the love
you have for your friends,
and once I have the key
and the last war begins,
they'll all be freed
at which point each
of you will be welcome
to fight alongside us,
and if you choose not to, well,
we'll save you anyway.
That is what we mean when we say,
"for all mankind."
Your move, my Liege.
Something's coming through.
Watch it, watch it.
Easy.
What the hell happened here?
Oh, gee. Where to begin.
Synced and corrected by Octavia
- www.addic7ed.com -