Almost there!
Stay with us, Emori. Stay with us!
Ok. Slow, slow. Murph.
I got it!
Raven, get the defibrillator.
- Where?
- There!
Hey. Come on, baby. Come on, baby.
Stay with me.
- Good. Now...
- I know how.
I've used one on myself.
Jax, what can I do?
Nothing yet.
- OK.
- Set.
Clear!
Come on!
One more time. Come on.
Raven, clear!
- Good job.
- Her pulse is weak.
She's lost too much blood.
- So we give her mine.
- Mine, too.
Murphy's a Nightblood. You're not.
- Wha...
- Just go back for the others.
I can't just leave her like this.
Unless you've done abdominal
surgery on yourself, too,
there's nothing more you can do.
I'll get her stable,
then take out the bar.
Raven, he's right.
They could be trapped.
You got to get them out.
- Alone? How? I...
- I don't know.
Never mind. I'll figure it out.
Just...
just save her.
Hey.
Once our friends are safe,
you have to go after Madi, OK?
You have to stop Cadogan.
Shepherd en route to bridge.
All disciples, stay alert.
The Shepherd's unit will be with him
guarding the door.
Too bad for them.
Grenades?
So more killing, that's the answer?
It's what we do.
Maybe we don't deserve to transcend.
Cover me.
We're too late.
What took you so long?
Our pier.
I took you fishing here once.
Why only once?
You jumped in.
Oh, I told you not to,
but you didn't listen.
You never listened.
She took after her mother.
You're not Callie.
No. This is who you chose.
We most often take the form of
the subject's greatest teacher
or the source of their greatest failure.
In the rare emotion-driven
species such as your own,
it can be their greatest love.
Seems you're faced
with all of the above.
Are you God?
For our purposes, you may
consider me your judge.
My judge? So they were right.
This is a trial, a test, not a war.
Correct.
The last of your kind to
stand before us... Becca...
refused the test.
Tell me... Dad,
is the human race now ready to join us?
Yes... we are ready.
Excellent.
Here's how it works. We talk,
I ask questions, you answer truthfully.
If you do not, I will know it.
If your answers are satisfactory,
your consciousness and that
of your entire species
will become one with ours.
You will transcend your human
form and become infinite.
If you fail to earn
this evolutionary leap,
you will be eliminated,
turned to crystal the way the Bardoans
and countless other
civilizations before them were.
Sound good?
The first question is about love.
So few species are given this gift,
yet you have attempted to erase
it in pursuit of this moment.
Why?
Pencils down.
My turn.
Get some water.
Sounds like they're getting closer.
Gaia took the last of
the water on her hunt.
I'll go to the river.
I hate waiting.
Done too much of it.
Trust me, I know.
But Octavia and Clarke can
take care of themselves.
Thank you.
That's what friends are for.
Friends, huh?
Can... friends do this?
Oh, they're back!
Form up! Attack on my orders!
What the hell are you doing here?
Saving our asses again.
Thank you.
It's what Hatch would do.
- Stone's right through there.
- Copy that.
The rest of you beat it
unless you want a lung
full of pulverized bunker.
Hey! We've got people down there.
So you do. Hear that, boys?
- Yep.
- Set phasers to stun.
You got it.
It's not Jackson. He's fine.
In Sanctum treating Emori.
Murphy's with them.
It's got to be Echo or Niylah then.
Why not the others?
There are no others.
Gabriel's dead. Cadogan
has Madi on Bardo.
Clarke and Octavia went to get her back.
They're to return for us
so we can help stop him.
Fire in the hole!
Then let's do that.
How? Cadogan will be
mobilizing his army for war.
We got 10 people.
With Sheidheda dead, Wonkru will fight.
- We go to Sanctum first.
- Fire in the hole.
Wonkru will lose, Indra.
Miller's right.
What we need is a
distraction, not a fight,
a way to get a small team past
their army to kill Cadogan.
Energy weapons.
Their weapons require energy, too.
Too bad we won't be able to
see what we're firing ours at.
Maybe we will.
Look what I found.
Hope!
More importantly, we're
through the collapse.
Good. Then let's go.
Wait. What about Gaia?
I'm sorry. Clarke and Octavia
are in trouble on Bardo.
Sounds familiar.
Indra, we can't wait for her.
Slow down. We still don't have a plan
that doesn't end with all of us dead.
Actually, I think Jordan was
just about to tell us one.
This one would make my father proud.
For my first trick,
I will make an army appear.
I'm offline. Weapons not responsive.
- I've got nothing.
- None of us do.
This is not the stone room.
The distraction can still work.
Insertion team, go now!
Copy that. Echo, lead the way.
The rest of you, into the trees!
The last war is here!
Their weapons are down.
Why aren't they attacking?
Move, move, move, move!
Well, they're distracted.
Yeah. Long enough for us to die.
We all will die.
When is out of our control.
This is a good how.
She's as stable as she's
gonna get. It's time.
Jax.
Thank God.
Raven got you out?
Yeah. She and Wonkru
just left for Bardo.
Without you?
I'm not leaving you again.
Whatever happens next,
we stick together.
I am glad you are safe.
Now how about my reunion?
What can I do?
Help hold her steady
while I take this out.
If she moves,
it'll cause even more damage.
- You understand?
- Yeah.
On 3.
1...
2...
3.
Hey, hey!
Hey. Come on. Emori, Emori! Emori!
She's bleeding out.
I have to get in there
surgically and find the...
Hurry up!
No, Emori!
Adrenaline.
What are you doing?
Do something! Come on! Do something!
You're a doctor! Please!
No.
No, no, no, no.
Hey, hey.
Emori. No.
Emori, please. Emori, please.
Take out her mind drive.
- Please.
- Please what?
Put her mind in your head?
We know from Clarke and
Josephine how that ends.
Fine.
- I'll do it myself.
- Mur...
If you died
and I could see you again,
I would do the same thing.
I got this.
You do realize that if
Clarke can't stop the test
then we are buying time for Wanheda
to be the witness for the human race.
Can I ask you something?
If she gets it done,
will my brother transcend?
No. Shepherd's passage, "Book of Bardo,"
Chapter 1, Verse 6.
"Death is the end, my friend.
Only the living shall transcend."
Must have slept through that class.
- What?
- If she does take the test,
then today's the end.
Either way, transcendence
or extinction...
I would have liked to
live a little first.
Same.
Sorry to interrupt.
Ohh!
- What happened here?
- We did.
Don't tell me Cadogan killed Madi.
Worse than killed her.
Clarke went in after
him to stop the test.
- Went in?
- How do you know
you weren't followed?
Hey. You can relax.
The disciples have their hands full
with Wonkru right now.
What, you brought an army here?
They're not here to fight.
It was a distraction to get us inside
- so we can kill Cadogan.
- The disciples don't know that.
If Clarke can't stop the test
to determine whether or not
the human race deserves to transcend
while what's left of the
human race is fighting a war...
- That would be bad.
- Worse than bad.
If we fail, the transcendents send Gem9.
The spy understands.
Look. I'm sorry for
what I did to you, OK?
I wasn't myself.
We'll make friends later.
Right now, we have to stop the war.
Levitt, on me.
I'm going with them.
Raven, get that bridge open.
You don't see that every day.
Why am I still here?
You know why.
Lexa.
I'm not her, Clarke.
I know.
The test isn't over?
No. I'm sorry. We can't stop
what's been set in motion.
Your species must now
be judged through you.
This man was unarmed, no threat to you,
yet you killed him.
Why?
He killed my daughter.
Is Madi dead?
No, but she will be because of him.
So your need for
revenge is more important
than the fate of the entire human race?
It's not revenge. It's justice.
Clarke...
_
You don't know my pain.
You're wrong.
During the test, I
sense every part of you.
I'm feeling your pain right now.
Really?
Then feel me holding Lexa as she dies.
Feel me seeing someone
else wear my mother's face.
Feel me murder my best friend
to save my child,
only to have her die anyway.
Feel that.
You suffer
and inflict suffering on others.
Pain begets pain. That's
not justice, Clarke.
You say you do these things
to protect your people,
but you're all one... people.
That much Cadogan had right.
He created a world without love
to get to you.
He killed my child to get to you.
Have you ever considered
that you're the problem?
How dare you judge me
when you annihilate entire species
because they don't
live up to your ideals?
Have I pulled the lever
to commit genocide?
Yes, I have.
And did love make me do this?
You're damn right it did!
But what's your excuse?
You play games with people
and call yourselves higher beings.
You are no better than
the murderers I've killed,
and you are no better than me!
I am sorry for all you have lost.
You've borne so much...
But if you are humanity,
then I'm afraid humanity is not worthy
of taking the next step.
It has been decided.
_
I remember that.
The place we first met.
Love at first knife to throat.
Oh, you are so beautiful.
John, where are we?
Josephine called it the mindspace.
If it were up to me, I would
have chosen our cave, but...
I died.
You did.
Not acceptable.
Hmm.
You put my mind drive in your head.
Two minds, one body. You'll die, too.
You have to take it out.
Without you, I'd just
be surviving, Emori.
- I wouldn't be living.
- No.
Hey, hey, hey.
I would take a few more hours with you
over forever without.
No, no, no.
You can't do this.
I won't let you do this, so wake up.
- Emori.
- Wake up.
Just wake up! Wake up!
Wake up! Wake up!
Jackson! Jackson, wake him up!
- Emori.
- Don't let him do this.
Jackson! John, John!
- Stop, stop, hey.
- Don't! Let go of me!
This is OK with me.
- No. It's not OK with me.
- It's OK. It's OK.
What is that?
What?
The last time I asked you to dance,
you stabbed me with a butcher knife.
Relationships.
Yeah.
♪ But I hear your call ♪
♪ Hold on now ♪
♪ We're going home ♪
♪ If we make it or we don't ♪
♪ We won't be alone ♪
♪ When I see your light shine ♪
♪ Some things are simple,
hard to ignore, they say ♪
♪ The truth is like that ♪
♪ We're getting colder,
so far from the shore ♪
♪ I say ♪
♪ The world is like that ♪
♪ I can't see you ♪
♪ But I hear your call ♪
♪ Hold on now ♪
Clarke?
Oh, that can't be good.
What have I done?
Clarke, wait!
Did you take the test?
Tell me what happened.
I failed.
It should have been you, not me.
They should have picked you first.
So that's it?
We don't transcend?
We're wiped out? It's over?
Well, can we change their minds?
I don't know.
I need to be with Madi.
There's not much time.
Clarke, wait!
Ah. Touching a pulsar.
What could go wrong?
No way.
Wait. Where's Earth?
About 42 billion light years away.
You read our thoughts
and take the form of someone we love.
Very good.
Yours is an interesting choice.
Not your real mother,
yet her opinion of
you mattered even more.
You fear her judgment.
Am I here to talk about me?
Why are you here?
The test is over.
As you know, Clarke failed.
How can that be?
Clarke sacrificed everything
for us so that we didn't have to.
She gave up her soul
so we could keep ours.
She committed atrocities.
She was trying to save us.
She doomed you. I'm sorry.
Are you?
Because to me, it looks
like you don't feel anything.
Have we made mistakes? Yes.
Clarke, me, all of us,
but we were just trying to survive.
I'm not saying we're ready now,
and if you don't want
us to join you, fine...
but at least let us live,
keep trying to do better.
We will. We have.
You say you have,
yet even now you are poised and
on the brink of self-extermination.
Look.
You say you're trying to do better,
but all I see are two tribes
of frightened creatures
willing to kill the
other to save themselves.
But they're not fighting.
It was just a distraction.
This proves nothing.
They will fight, Raven,
like they always do.
You can't possibly know that.
Hmm.
Let the games begin.
Stop! What the hell are you doing?
They can't see or hear you.
You cannot stop this.
No one can.
Who fired? No one respond!
Levitt, slow down!
Hold your fire! Don't shoot!
Hold!
Wait, wait, wait!
Listen to me.
This is not the last war.
We don't achieve
transcendence through violence.
Cadogan was wrong.
We're being tested right now, all of us.
You were saying?
Put down your weapons!
Nonsense.
History is written by the victors.
Let's try this again.
Man down!
Return fire!
Levitt, no!
Octavia, wait!
Damn it!
Indra, cover me!
Fire!
Oh, my God.
Echo, you're hit.
What the hell are you doing?
I lost Bellamy.
I will not lose his sister.
Don't you see?
Despite the beauty that
humans are capable of,
you can't break free from
the cycle of violence.
Hi, baby. I'm here.
Aunty O!
You have to stop the war.
- I got this.
- Stop the war.
This is who you are.
That's why you failed the test.
I'm so sorry I failed you.
I failed everyone.
It's time for us to go, Raven.
The end of the human race is here.
You can do this.
Jordan, Hope, don't let them die.
The dead don't transcend.
You're gonna be OK.
Indra! Indra, hold your fire!
_
Indra is not in command here!
I am, and I say...
_
Enough!
What the hell are we doing here?
You swore an oath to
fight for all mankind.
Well, look around you!
We are mankind! We are one crew!
If I kill you,
I kill myself.
If we keep killing each other,
there won't be anyone left to save!
Our fight is over, Indra!
I hope you know what you're doing.
We're unarmed.
I know you're afraid to walk away
from everything you've spent
your lives training for.
I am, too.
My brother believed, as you do,
that transcendence, whatever that means,
is within reach.
He died for that belief,
and for that, he'll never get there,
never transcend.
I don't know what I believe,
but I do know that if we fight this war
we don't deserve to
find out if he was right.
We don't deserve to survive.
We fail, we die.
She's reaching them.
I've been to war, and let me tell you
the only way to win...
is not to fight.
Nice speech.
No. Stay with me!
This does not end here.
Echo, no! No!
Pump her heart. Do it now!
Sir, what are your orders?
For all mankind.
- For all mankind.
I told you. We can change.
We just need more time.
Please.
- What are you doing?
- What?
I said...
What's happening?
No pain.
Oh, my God.
This is what I saw when I was adjusting.
Bellamy was right.
Jax.
We're glowing.
Oh, now that is cool.
Raven went in.
It's OK.
I know you don't want to leave me...
but you have to go now.
This gives you a chance to live.
Let go, Madi. Just let go.
I'll be OK.
I love you forever, Madi,
forever.
Is anyone here?
Murphy?
Emori?
Hey, girl! Hi!
Where are we gonna live, girl, huh?
Where are we gonna live?
Today, water and shelter.
Tomorrow, food, OK?
Picasso, come!
Damn it!
Picasso?
Please come back!
I don't want to be alone.
You're not.
What do you want?
To explain.
There's no need.
I get it. I bear it so
they don't have to again.
Such a curious species.
You've added so much to us already.
I'm glad to have been wrong about you.
Wait.
Does that mean...
you're here to take me with you?
No. You can never join us, Clarke.
Your actions must have a cost.
Just mine?
Am I the only human
being who ever sinned?
Of course not,
but you are the only test
subject from any species
anywhere in the universe
since the dawn of time
who committed murder during a test.
I'd do it again.
Madi knew you'd say that.
Madi's with you then?
In a manner of speaking, yes.
Her consciousness has joined ours.
She's at peace.
She'll never feel
pain, she'll never die.
She knew that living here
without anyone her own age to love
is something you wouldn't
have wanted for her,
even if it meant you being alone.
I suppose that choice was made easier
with the realization you wouldn't be.
Transcendence is a choice?
You can choose to come back?
Of course,
though until now no one ever had.
Wow! There's all these fish!
There won't be offspring,
and they won't join us when they die.
None of them seem to care.
Hey. There she is.
Clarke.
A curious species indeed.
Picasso!
There she is! Hi!
Synced and corrected by Octavia
- www.addic7ed.com -