Herkes dinlesin.
Sabah bir cinayet ihbarı aldık.
Kurban 8.45'te köpek bakıcısı tarafından
evinde bulunmuş.
Tanrım! Bu Franzia!
Bu Johnny Franzia'nın işi.
Adam bana takıntılı.
Sonunda ortaya çıktı.
- Yine mi bu?
- Evet, yine bu.
Johnny Franzia son on yıldır kıyım yapıyor.
Her işlediği cinayeti
benim yüzüme vuruyor.
Bak, yerde oyun kartları var.
Kartları her gördüğünde
aynı şeyi söylüyorsun.
Kartlardan kaç kişide var,
biliyor musun?
O zaman bunu açıkla.
Johnny Franzia'nın meşhur sözü:
"İkide keramet olmaz."
Şimdi de eve bakın.
İki koltuk, iki tablo, iki yastık.
Lambalar üç tane.
Sence lambalar Franzia'nın umurunda mı?
Saçmalıyorsun.
Bu yüzden senin
baş düşmanın yok Terry.
Yanlış detaylara takılıyorsun.
Belki de tüm suçları çözdüğüm için
baş düşmanım yoktur.
Bana söyleyeceğin en b**tan söz.
Çeviri: oyington
Bizi çağırmışsınız, Yüzbaşı.
Cinayeti başka birine veriyorum.
Ne?
Franzia davasını benden alıyor musunuz?
Olamaz.
Sizinle iletişime geçti, değil mi?
Seni temin ederim, geçmedi.
Bugüne kadar Johnny Franzia'yı
hiç duymamıştım.
Tabii, çoğu siz gelmeden önceydi.
Aslında buraya geldiğiniz ilk yıl
Franzia olduğunuzdan emindim.
Şimdi fark ettim ki
tamamen saçmalıyormuşum.
Yoksa?
I have no investment in this backstory.##########################################################
- Tabii.
- Davayı sizden alıyorum.
Çünkü ikiniz de çocuk için
daha az mesai istemiştiniz.
Hem bu hafta Santiago'nun
büyük sunumu var.
Üniformalı memurların mevzi
yerlerini canlandıran deneme
programımız fonlanırsa
it will represent a significant
reform for the NYPD.
Sir, we can take care of Mac
and still do both of our jobs.
Trust me, we've got this whole
parenting thing figured out.
It's true.
We're great, and Mac is great.
I mean, the only teeny-tiny issue
is that he isn't
pulling himself up yet,
but the window for that
is 9 to 12 months.
So the fact that he's 10 months
old and isn't doing it yet
doesn't mean that we're bad parents.
- _
- And I was reading that Simone Biles
went straight from crawling to walking.
So, yeah, I guess
I should be "concerned"
that my son is on the same track
as a multiple gold medal winner.
I mean, get real, sir.
So, yeah, Mac's having
a little trouble pulling up,
but did that convince you
to give us more responsibility?
Look, if you promise you can handle it,
I'll put you back
on the John Franzo case.
Franzia. Johnny Franzia.
How could you forget that? Unless...
- Get out.
- You got it.
Thank you for letting me
stay with you, Diaz.
I am sorry for imposing.
I assumed I'd be back
with Kevin by now.
Oh, couple's therapy isn't going well?
Well, we're not back together,
even after three full sessions.
That's three hours,
more if you include travel time.
Why would I include travel time?
It's a longer drive for me
than for Kevin,
so I'm putting in more effort.
Hmm, I wonder why it's not going well.
Well, Kevin says it's because
so all I care about is work.t.
But if that's true,
why did I leave work
13 minutes early today
to move in with you?
Well, you can stay as long as you like.
You're quiet, you're neat.
You're the perfect roommate.
I think Kevin would disagree.
He told Dr. Cheryl
I'm a sore loser at Scrabble.
How would he know that
when I win 78% of our matches?
Wow, you're a lot chattier
than I remember you being.
Oh, sorry. I promise...
I won't obsess about Kevin
the whole time I'm here.
Okay. Great.
Although I may break that promise,
because according to Kevin, I'm a liar.
Ah, damn it, two of clubs is blank.
That's not like him.
So what are we missing here?
Two chairs, two paintings.
Oh, my God, the lamps.
But you told Terry that
Franzia didn't care about lamps.
No, he loves lamps.
I was just feeling attacked,
so I lashed out,
but why three identical lamps
instead of two?
Because they're not actually identical.
The shade on this one is darker, and...
- Ooh!
- It's a blacklight.
Yes, frickin' two of clubs.
Turn off the overheads.
Franzia!
Hey, so don't freak out,
but apparently there
are several other groups
presenting reform proposals
to One Police Plaza,
and only one will get funding.
Why would that make me freak out?
Because you can be
a little competitive.
That's not true.
No one is less competitive than me.
No one.
Anyway, uh, here's
who you're up against.
Alan Peters. Dud.
Mike Lynch. Dud.
Tad Green. Dud!
Austin Grant.
Who's Austin Grant? Not a dud?
Oh, he's a dud, but he's a hot dud.
He's a "hud."
He gets everything handed to him
because he looks so good in a uniform.
Ugh, and he's pitching
predictive algorithmic policing.
That's just high-tech racial profiling.
Okay, look, if this guy
is style over substance,
we just need to give you some style.
Check this out.
Tiny Terry won the
Little Mister Michigan pageant.
You just happen to have
a video of yourself
as a seven-year-old on your phone?
Big Terry's proud of Tiny Terry.
Look, the point is, I can help you.
Terry! Terry!
It's him. It's really Franzia.
Don't ask how I know
'cause it has nothing to do with lamps.
Jake, what are you doing here?
What are you doing here?
You're supposed to be
getting Mac from day care!
He's finally down.
Did you miss anything important
with your case?
Yes, because jokers are wild,
Charles went to the "Joker"
stairs, and there was graffiti
of the victim's name
written on a bus stop.
So Charles got on the bus,
took it to the end of the line,
where there was a payphone ringing.
He picked it up, and there
was a voice on the other end
that told him a riddle.
- What was the riddle?
- I don't know.
He had to go before he could
tell me because he noticed
that his kitchen window
was mysteriously unlocked.
Stupid Franzia is probably
in his house right now
trying to murder him and his family.
At least he's not here
trying to murder me and Mac.
I appreciate you trying
to make me feel better, Ames,
but we both know
you're grasping at straws.
Thank God.
Charles is fine. Nobody in the house.
I would have been so jealous.
I'm sorry, babe.
I'd say I'd take over Mac stuff
for the week,
but I have to rewrite my whole
presentation to be snappier,
and, also, according to Terry,
I need to learn
how to walk with my shoulders
and not my feet.
It's okay. What you're doing
is super important.
I'll just scale back
and let Charles run point
on the Franzia case.
No. None of us are scaling back.
We can be good parents without
sacrificing our careers.
We just have to work as a team.
You know what? Yes, you're right.
We got this.
All we need is each other.
There's been a lice outbreak
at day care,
and they're closing
for the next two days.
What? No!
We need so much more than each other.
Ugh, damn it.
None of our regular babysitters
are available.
And my parents are out of town,
and my brother David can't help
because he's in Sudan digging wells
for somebody or something...
I don't know, I hung up on him.
My dad's out, too.
That's all he said,
didn't give a reason.
Wait, I've got it.
Let's just let Mac watch TV all day.
Jake, we've talked about this.
No screen time for Mac
until he turns two.
Ugh.
All this stress is making my head itch.
Yeah, it's weird... I've
actually been itching myself.
No! Lice! Scratching it makes it worse.
- Is that true?
- I don't know.
We don't have time to know what's true.
Okay, okay, let's just stay calm.
When I had lice in the fifth grade,
my mom put a bunch
of maple syrup in my hair,
and it smothered them to death,
it was actually kind of cool.
You can hear their tiny screams.
No, that's an old home remedy,
and day care actually recommends
a place where you go, and they
comb the lice out for you.
I bet we'll be in and out
in 20 minutes.
Six hours? Who has that kind of time?
So now what?
I mean, I guess
there is one last option.
- Please don't say it.
- It worked for me in fifth grade.
I really don't want to.
It is kind of cool
to hear the screaming.
Okay, fine, we'll do the syrup.
We're gonna do the syrup!
♪ Come on
♪ Oh
Oh, Amy, what is that
enchanting new perfume?
It's syrup, Scully.
And it is working. Hmm-hmm.
I think you just made Scully horny.
Ugh.
And then he called her Cheryl,
not Dr. Cheryl,
a clear attempt to delegitimize her.
Obviously, I agree,
she has zero legitimacy.
I mean, she calls herself Dr. Cheryl.
Then Kevin brings up how
Cheddar's French comprehension
has regressed.
Cheddar's tutor says
it's because we're not
speaking enough at home.
The worst part
is we used to share socks.
With an odd number,
that was a tense negotiation.
Enough!
All you do is talk about Kevin.
This needs to stop.
I'm sorry...
I wish I could stop thinking
about him, but he was
my husband for 20 years.
If you know how I could just
erase him from my memory,
I'd love to hear it.
We could get really drunk.
Yes, let's try that.
Jake, Jake, Franzia was in my house.
I didn't see anything last night,
but when I showered this morning,
a new riddle appeared
in the steam on the mirror.
Oh, cool. Cool, cool, cool, cool.
I also saw a riddle while showering.
But we didn't shower this morning.
No, I know, it's just Charles
and I have this agreement
that when I miss something
important on the case,
he pretends like I'm still
involved... it's normal.
Anyways, I'm sure our shower
riddles were the same.
No, I'm sure yours was better.
Well, just to be sure,
why don't you text me yours,
and I'll make sure
it's the same as mine,
and then we can decode it together
- after Ames and I find a sitter.
- Great.
Ooh, we already have three applicants.
Great. Hire them.
I think we should interview them first.
But what if they're bad?
This really feels like fate
because I was arrested in this precinct
literally a year ago to the day.
Here, I brought a toy
for the little guy.
Oh, thanks. That's very nice of you.
He's so soft.
Your son's really gonna
enjoy cuddling him.
Want to see me cuddle him?
I love cuddling.
Well, this went south very quickly.
I consider myself
a bit of a Mary Poppins.
Oh, how so?
♪ I'm your nanny,
I'll slap your fanny ♪
♪ Slap, slap, slap
♪ Your fat little fanny
Yeah, it's gonna be a no.
I got to get back to Franzia,
so feels like we should go
with the cuddler.
No, as much as I want to work,
we can't leave our son
with some weirdo.
Maybe we ask someone in the precinct?
Everyone's working.
Not everyone.
Sure, I'll watch Mac.
Don't worry, I've padded
all the sharp edges in here.
Wow. You already baby-proofed it?
Ah, it's my nap room.
You can take a nap anywhere in here.
Every surface is like a bed.
- Huh.
- Works for us.
Okay. Sorry, the babysitter
thing took a little longer
than I was expecting,
but I solved part of the riddle.
A cat has ten lives.
I think the lives are numbers.
Wow, that's so smart.
I already solved the riddle.
It's a phone number.
But you're here now.
We can call together.
Okay, yeah, I guess.
I mean, maybe he'll have
a cool scary modulated voice
or something.
- Yeah, yeah.
- All right.
Hello.
Oh, my God, he does.
You solved my riddle, Detective Boyle.
And Detective Peralta!
I'm still on your tail,
and your sick game is finally...
Help! Help!
Oh, seriously?
Uh, Franzia, I got to go real quick.
What? You have to go?
Boyle will explain,
but I'm still on your tail.
And if you think
the jokers are really wild...
Jake!
All right, I'm coming! Damn it!
- What happened?
- Is Mac okay?
Mac's fine. It's me.
There was one unpadded corner,
and I stubbed my toe real bad.
Look.
- Ugh!
- Oh, God!
I'm sorry, I got to go to the hospital.
Yeah, immediately, for so many reasons.
- Come on.
- Gosh.
Is he okay?
He's fine.
Ames, I'm sorry, but I think
we're all out of babysitters.
No. There is one option left.
His first screen time, this is amazing.
Which "Transformers" movie
should he watch first?
There's an argument
to be made for "Bumblebee,"
as it is a prequel.
- Jake.
- All right, fine.
Just let it auto-play whatever
garbage it wants, and let's go.
Okay. Here you go, Mac.
Here you go.
Yeah, we deserve that.
Oh, I am hungover. How you feeling?
Not good at all.
You were supposed
to watch out for me, Diaz.
Good news is,
the heavy drinking worked.
You didn't mention Kevin one time.
Oh, that is an accomplishment.
Unfortunately, it appears
that I did think about him
at least once last night.
What do you mean?
At 3:30 a.m.,
I seem to have sent Kevin...
A digital phallus portrait.
A digital phallus portrait?
What is that?
[gasps] Oh, no, you sent him
a [bleep] pic.
Shh. Shh.
Please stop crying. I'm so tired.
Maybe we'd all be better rested
if we hadn't woken up at 3:00 a.m.
I'm sorry, I've never slept
with syrup in my hair before.
I didn't know that was gonna happen.
Ants! Ants in the bed!
- Who?
- There's ants in the bed!
There's ants! There's ants!
My presentation is today,
and I am not showing up
in a shower cap.
What are we gonna do?
There's only one thing left to do.
We're gonna blow-dry these sons
of bitches straight to hell.
_
Got to say, worked great.
Although I guess my hair took
it a little better than yours.
And why the glasses?
Mac knocked my last contacts
into the toilet
while I was blow-drying.
Got to hand it to him,
it's a solid prank.
Although I must say,
this look kind of works for you.
Jake, we don't have time
for your nerd fetish.
We are so late.
I know. You know what?
Let's not waste any more time
looking for babysitters.
We'll just take Mac into work with us.
See, Ames, we got this.
Yeah, this is not gonna be hard.
You want to know why?
'Cause we're great parents.
In fact, we forgot Mac.
We left our child inside.
- Oh.
- Uh, get the keys.
Okay, I'll take Mac first
so you can start practicing
your presentation.
- Okay.
- Jake, I think
I figured something out
about the toolbox.
- Toolbox?
- Franzia sent me a toolbox.
It turned out to be a puzzle.
It was so boring.
Charles, it wasn't boring.
I know what you're doing.
- Just tell me what happened.
- Okay, so I ran it for prints.
And there was a partial on the wrench.
It belongs to a guy named Eric Marsh
who works as a handyman
in the victim's building.
- We have to bring him in.
- Already done.
He's in interrogation right now,
- just waiting for you.
- Oh...
But I have Mac for the next hour.
I can't run an interrogation.
Unless...
How did your prints end up on a wrench
that was sent to this police station?
That wrench went missing two weeks ago.
I thought someone took it
out of the back of my truck.
Of course, that sounds...
Totally reasonable, Eric.
Or should I call you by your real name?
Johnny Franzia.
I don't know who that is.
Uh-oh. Something stinks.
Something stinks real bad.
- Did you poop?
- No.
You did. You pooped.
Oh, God, it's everywhere.
What did you eat, buddy?
Today? I had some oatmeal.
Here's what's gonna happen.
I'm gonna lie you down,
I'm gonna take your pants off,
and I'm gonna wipe your little tushy.
What is going on?
I actually have the same question.
Hold on one second. Jake?
Why did I send Kevin
an obscene picture?
Relax. It's not a big deal.
You were just flirting.
No, if I were flirting,
I would have sent him
a scatter plot
of educational attainment
versus caloric intake
in Jacobin France.
This is as if I've sent him
a bar graph.
Are bar graphs bad?
It reduces robust data sets
to a single point.
Get your head out of your ass!
I'm sorry... I'm just panicking,
thinking about what Kevin
will do when he sees it.
Wait, you don't think he's seen it yet?
No, Kevin only checks his email
once a day at exactly 4:00 p.m.
- You didn't text it to him?
- We're not teens.
Let's delete it off his computer, then.
Yes, that could work.
Kevin has virtual office hours
at 2:00 p.m.
At the same time, Cheddar
will be taking a French lesson
with his tutor, Monsieur Arnaud.
We only have one hour exactement.
- Here is Kevin's laptop.
- Great.
"Dear Kevin, attached please
find a picture of my penis.
Sincerely, Raymond Holt." Deleted.
Cheddar! Non, s'il vous plait, non.
French class must have ended early.
- Shut up.
- Shh.
Hello? Is someone upstairs?
♪ Hello, Charles, fill me in ♪
♪ Any breaks in the case? ♪
If you sing everything as a lullaby,
Mac won't wake up.
♪ I understand ♪
♪ The handyman has an alibi ♪
♪ But I found something else ♪
- You sound great.
- Thank you.
♪ The lab techs analyzed
Franzia's phone call ♪
♪ There were two other voices ♪
♪ In the background ♪
Oh, who's a good boy?
Who wants another bite?
Wait. Is that Scully feeding Mac?
Was Franzia inside the building?
No, his voice is playing over a speaker
in the background.
Franzia must've bugged the precinct,
and he was listening to it
when we called him.
Shh, shh.
♪ But why would he ♪
♪ Bug Scully's nap closet? ♪
♪ 'Cause he didn't bug the closet ♪
♪ He bugged something brought inside ♪
♪ Oh, my God, Franzia ♪
♪ Was the weird babysitter ♪
♪ He gave the bug right to you ♪
♪ Son of a bitch ♪
Amy, we got to talk.
I just got a call
from One Police Plaza.
They said they were trying
to reach you all morning.
Mac broke my phone. What do they want?
They moved your presentation up.
You're on in 20 minutes!
- 20 minutes?
- Amy!
We know where Franzia is.
We're gonna go arrest him.
I need you to take Mac.
No, you need to take Mac!
I have to go right now.
So do I! What do we do?
I guess we could call
that creepy babysitter
- you liked so much.
- The babysitter is Franzia!
Even better! Two birds with one stone!
We bring him to you!
We're not giving our baby
to a serial killer!
- Oh, grow up!
- Come on!
Amy, if we miss this presentation,
that's the end of the pilot program!
Jake, SWAT is on their way.
We have to go to Franzia's now.
This is our best chance
at police reform!
- Franzia, Lieutenant, Franzia!
- Reform, Boyle, Reform!
Okay, enough!
Charles is right.
Jake has waited years for this.
No, he can make the arrest without me.
Without you, there is no presentation.
I'll take Mac.
- Are you sure?
- Yes, absolutely.
All right, now go.
Everyone, get out of here.
Come on.
- I love you.
- Love you.
Oh, crap, there's Austin.
Oh, damn, he is a "hud."
Okay, okay. Let's just be cool.
- Yeah.
- Here, hold my glasses.
Hey, Austin, long time no... mm, see.
Santiago, are you okay?
Yeah, great. You look good.
Thanks, I know, and you have
a very brave hairstyle?
Thank you.
Sergeant Santiago, we're ready for you.
I look insane. What am I gonna do?
Okay, style over substance
is clearly out,
but if anyone can substance
the crap out of this,
it's Amy Santiago.
You're right, I can do this.
Substance over style.
Mm!
Come on, Amy.
Hello?
Raymond, what are you doing here?
Kevin, I didn't know you were home.
I came by to get a book.
"The History of The Crusades:
Volume Three, 1123 to 1137."
- Why did you need it?
- I had an urgent question.
- About what?
- The atabeg of Mosul.
- Jikirmish?
- Zengi.
But you already know
everything about Zengi.
True, it was Diaz's question, um...
and I was embarrassed for her.
And what was your question, Diaz?
I wanted to know who Zengi is.
Yes, that is embarrassing.
I can see why you tried
to cover for her.
Well, if that's all...
It is. Uh, just Zengi.
Just Zengi.
All right, then. Goodbye.
- How'd it go?
- Good!
They liked the thesis,
and I was clear on the data.
Just one problem...
I realized halfway through
that these sweatpants
are from a bachelorette party
I went to,
and they say WAP on the butt.
I told them it stands
for "We All Police."
- Hey, wish me luck in there.
- Did your teeth get whiter?
That's an illusion.
My smile is so symmetrical,
it makes my teeth seem brighter.
Well, good luck. Oops.
What the hell?
Austin, we're...
Everything okay?
- He peed himself.
- No.
That's funny... same thing happened
to Alex Nelson
at Little Mister Michigan.
What?
Tiny Terry did what he had to do.
So right as we get there,
Franzia disappears into these
crazy underground tunnels.
So we have to switch over
to night vision...
Charles, it's all so awesome,
but I actually have to stop you
because I got to go.
I have to feed this baby
some mushed-up avocado...
Oh, my God.
What happened? Is Mac okay?
He just pulled himself up.
Hey, did Kevin seem weird
to you when we told him
we were only there for that book?
You think he didn't believe us?
No, he seemed sad.
I think he was disappointed
that you were there
for the book and not for him.
Maybe you should let him know
you've been missing him.
Huh, well, it might be worth a shot.
- What did you just do?
- I texted him a picture
of my penis, like you suggested.
No. Ugh!
I meant for you to call him
and tell him you've
been thinking about him.
- Why didn't you say that?
- I thought it was understood.
Hold on. He's writing back.
- Well, what did he say?
- It's a link to a graph.
It's a scatter plot
with a very robust data set.
Well...
That escalated quickly.
Hey.
Hey, how'd the presentation go?
Well, they just called, and...
- I won.
- What?
I have authorization
to start immediately.
Wait, you won? That's amazing.
Why aren't you more excited?
Why aren't you dork-dancing?
'Cause you had to miss your thing,
and I didn't want to rub it in.
So I celebrated in the hallway
before I walked in.
Yes! Yeah!
Oh! Oh!
How'd it go here with Mac?
Fine. Mellow.
He pulled himself up.
Wait, what?
That's huge! He's in the window!
Why are you downplaying this?
Well, I just figured
you would be bummed that you missed it.
Ugh, this sucks.
You didn't get to arrest Franzia.
I didn't get to see Mac pull up.
I guess we really can't do it all.
I don't know.
I mean, you got to do the work thing,
and I got to do the parent thing.
So...
together...
we did do it all.
Yeah, I guess you're right.
- It still totally sucks, though.
- Yeah, I'm really bummed.
Yeah. I'm gonna get ready for bed.
Okay. You're gonna wake up Mac
and see if he'll pull up, aren't you?
Obviously, he is not sleeping
until he does it again.
All right, well, don't go without me,
'cause I want to see it.
Sync & corrections by emeline-whovian
www.addic7ed.com